JEESOO KIM

jeesooxkim@gmail.com | (440) 533-9063 | github: jkim502

SUMMARY

Backend software engineer experienced in expanding large scale AI applications through agile feature development. Key strengths include swift adaptivity, edge case detection, clear technical communication, cross-team collaboration, and fast learning. Specializes in machine learning aided language processing and delivery to clients.

PROFESSIONAL HISTORY

Software Engineer at IBM Watson

Austin, TX | August 2019 - Present

Watson Assistant

April 2020 - Present

- Integrating and extending Watson Assistant with commercial messaging platforms such as Slack, Facebook and also live agent service desks such as Zendesk, Salesforce, with state-of-the-art Watson Al
- Engineering robust E2E automated testing framework for all Watson Assistant chat integrations, aiming to reduce testing time and improve overall product stability and maintainability
- Iterating chat feature design for intuitiveness through close collaboration with front-end and offering management

 Watson Discovery

 August 2019 April 2020
 - Engineered and refactored the central information retrieval model training microservice to support new projectlevel training feature, and delivered to a major release within four months of entry-level position
 - · Crafted and improved tests in Go and Java to improve overall stability and proactive bug discovery
 - Provided 24/7 on call support for clients, delivering immediate aid through swift and adaptive problem solving

Computer Vision Researcher at JHU Collaborative Robotics Lab

Baltimore, MD | June 2018 - January 2019

- · Designed novel method for intuitively programming robots utilizing a 2D table-top light-projected control interface
- Developed fingertip recognition and tracking using OpenCV in Python3 using depth and color data from Xbox Kinect and video feed from top-down camera

Embedded Systems Intern at DKU Embedded Systems Lab Yongin, South Korea | June 2017 – November 2017

- Researched OS file system and cache management improvement, focusing on utilizing non-volatile memory
- Co-authored publication "Analyzing and Modeling the Impact of Memory Latency and Bandwidth on Application Performance" describing the advantage of NVM in a multi-core environment, using a novel memory analysis framework

EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

Johns Hopkins University

May 2019

B.S. in Computer Science

· Focus in Machine Learning and Al Systems

SKILLS

Programming Languages JavaScript/TypeScript, Go, Java, Python, C++, SQL **Tools & Strategies** Kubernetes, Docker, Node, Express, NGINX, Test Automation, Agile/Scrum, etc.

PERSONAL INTERESTS

I speak English (native), Korean (native), German (proficient but unfortunately fading) *Talk to me about* the great outdoors (8 countries, 17 states), coffee & wine, bouldering, various instruments and music(violin, guitar/ukulele, vocal), mechanical keyboards, graphic design, computer graphics, AR & VR